As you probably already
know, I recently
left my job at
school to explore
new
horizons.  I
hope to become an
art teacher,
but right now it's all just
in the planning stages.
I also found a new
place for my
workshop, and that's very
exciting.  I've been dreaming
about this ever since
one of my first
clients reported
finding
three black dog
hairs in a package.  I was
very embarrassed, and I
realized that I
needed a proper
workspace.  Oh my
God.  Getting used to a
new routine
without school can be
strange and a little scary at times.  I do
n't know what the future holds for
me,
but I listen to
my mentors,
not least of whom are
wildflowers.  Before I
continue, I have to
tell you about
one plant.  She is
known as the
balsam root, and
this spring she gave
me incredible
life advice.  This
flower is a symbol of
this part of
Washington state, and at this time of
year it covers all the
hillsides.  It is
easily recognized by its
buttery yellow
flowers and
arrow-shaped
leaves.  But
the most interesting thing about this
plant is that what
we see doesn't
tell the whole
truth.  And I think that's
true for
each of us.  The whole
secret lies
underground.  There
is an
incredible root
system there that can be
used as
food or for medicinal
purposes.  The main
taproot
can reach several
feet deep to
find a water source.
Branched tendrils
dig into the soil,
preventing erosion.
This
survival mechanism is
vital in
conditions like mine, where it is
dry and hot this time of year
.  If you are
familiar with
American history, you have heard of the
Dust
Bowl disaster.  One of the
many reasons for what
happened was
farming methods that
removed native plants from their
native soil.  Without
their deep
root system,
the earth
would turn to
dust, blown away by
the winds.  This shows
how important these
plants are to the
survival of our
planet.  No matter how
beautiful a
plant is, without roots
it is short-lived.
Every little
intervention can
negatively affect
them, and ultimately they
cannot flourish and
grow.  Young flowers are
certainly beautiful and
delicate, but old
plants are an
incredible sight.
They are strong, lush, and
can easily
tolerate drought.
They inspire me.
It's a wonderful
reminder that the
invisible is the
most important part of
who we are.  I
learned the lesson of the
balsam root
and set a
goal for myself to strengthen my own
“root system”
to find
stability during
this very
difficult
transition period.
This year my life
has changed significantly.  I
realize that nothing will ever be the same again
.
It's
exciting and a little
scary at the same time.  I think we all
find ourselves at a
crossroads at some point in our lives, where we can
choose one of
several paths that will
lead us in completely
different directions.  I used to
look at these
options with
trepidation, afraid of
making the wrong
choice and taking my
life down a path I would
later regret.
But I began to believe
that we can find
self-fulfillment on
different
paths in life.  Perhaps
there are many
equally interesting and
worthwhile
journeys that one
could take.
I couldn't
sleep last night,
wondering if I had
made the right decision
by choosing new
teaching opportunities and
focusing on
my business.  But
despite the fear, I
realized that in
this case there is no
such thing as a "
wrong choice."
And I believe that in
many situations
where we have a choice, it's
how we
handle
our decision and what we
learn that makes it
worth it or not.  I am
very glad that this
transitional stage
fell in the spring.  This is
such a beautiful time of
renewal and
healing.  Last
but certainly not least
: I have
news regarding this
channel.  My brother
recently returned
from Australia after
almost a year of separation,
which was very difficult for me
.  As children,
we were very, very
close.  You
will definitely see
him in one of the
next videos.  He
generously
offered to
help me with the video, which is
fantastic because
I've always wanted to
learn how
to use a
real camera.  I
noticed some speculation in
the comments
about
who actually
makes these videos, and the
answer is me.
Mostly yes, although there
were a few times
when I asked for
help, but very
rarely.  I shoot on an iPhone
with a tripod, and I
really want to
learn how
to use a
professional camera,
so he's finally
going to teach me and
help me with the
filming until I
can do it on my
own.  This is so
exciting, I'm
very grateful to him, and
I hope that starting
next week you
will notice a significant
improvement in
video quality.  I wish you all a
wonderful week.
I have loved ones
who are very sick with the
same illness that we
will not name, and I am
very worried about them.
So I would appreciate
any thoughts or
prayers you may have, and I hope
you all
stay
safe and healthy.
Sending my love.
See you later.